JAYANTA GARU

React Developer

8917293473

in linkedin.com/in/jayanta-garu-69628a13a/

☑ jayanta.garu@gmail.com

☑ Bengaluru

9

Passport -: P1342705

SUMMARY

To seek challenging and growth oriented career, contributing to the success of the organization and at the same time enhance my knowledge and skills.

I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create cool digital experiences. My repertoire includes programming languages and tools such as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, Redux, Hook, AutoCAD and more.

EXPERIENCE

React Developer

Greet Labs Private Limited

~ 02/2019 - 09/2021 + Bengaluru, Karnataka

I am responsible for developing the architectural and functional flow using JavaScript and React.js for tracking of ideas associated with user involved in browser compatibility. Using React JS for creating reusable UI components (multi-field form elements, buttons and more).

- Hands on experience in developing single page applications in React
- Interact with the designer to suggest changes and to make sure the view he has about the design is translated into actual functionality.
- Demonstrating abilities to work in critical projects and also possess strong analytical and problem solving skill.
- Involving in Development, Review and Execution of the project modules.
- Good experience with Git Hub and GitLab.
- Redesigning, simplifying and implementing a new version of an existing applications for a better performance.

- React Developer

- TCTS
- $-\sim 09/2021$ 10/2021 + pune, Maharastra

I am responsible for developing the architectural and functional flow using JavaScript and React.js for tracking of ideas associated with user involved in browser compatibility. Using React JS for creating reusable UI components (multi-field form elements, buttons and more).

- Hands on experience in developing single page applications in React JS.
- Interact with the designer to suggest changes and to make sure the view he has about the design is translated into actual functionality.

SKILLS

FRONT-END

HTML 5 CSS3 BOOTSTRAP

JAVASCRIPT ES6 REACT

REDUX HOOK

IDE

VSCODE ATOM

TOOLS

GITHUB GITLAB SVN

AUTOCAD

PROJECTS

WICULTY LEARNING SOLUCTIONS PVT. LTD

Wiculty.com is a global E-Learning Platform providing software professional certification courses.

- I am responsible for Enhancing and creating style components for multiple usage of components using React JS.
- Suggested enhancements to product designs that would improve user experience.
- Integrated to the API's with the help of React Redux.
- Created maintainable, responsive code using the React JS and Bootstrap.

EXPERIENCE

GIS/CAD Engineer

AABSyS IT pvt

~ 03/2017 - 11/2018 + Bhubaneswar, Odisha

Hands on experience in producing technical CAD drawing and models for digitization of CAD data(.dwg). And doing the quality check of the team members files as per the client requirements.

- CAD/CAFM data digitization.
- Design infrastructure of workplace and new building's blueprint as per the client information.
- Most of the time we are using client remote app to design the model.
- Quality check of the team members files as per the client parameter within the delivery date.
- Learned different types of new software after the completion of the project.
- Created lots of built-in LISP interpreter by CMD for various project development.
- Managed team member problem and provided training to new folks.

PROJECTS

YELLOW CLASS

Yellow Class is a new-age fun-learning platform where kids can learn from a wide range of classes like dancing, drawing, personality development, creative writing and so on.

- Created a web application which allows marketing and support organizations to provide a visibility of their Product Hierarchies, order status and details of the delivery
- Enhanced the quality of inventory application mainly used by dealers/clients based on defects occurred.

T2R

TICKET 2 RESOLVE (T2R) is a tool that's provide Networking services to the Client...

 Responsible for the development of React Components and used Redux for state management to fulfill to client requirement.

EDUCATION

Gandhi Academy Of Technology And Engineering

Biju Pattnaik University of Technology

- ~ 2012 2016
- _ B.TECH

PASSIONS

Drawing	Traveling
Internet Surfing	Running

LANGUAGES

Hindi	••••
English	••••
Odia	

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 3 TIMES AWARDED AS EMPLOYEE OF THE MONTH.
- PARTICIPATED IN KHO-KHO GAME (NATIONAL) AT RAJASTHAN (2008-09).
- SUCCESSFULLY COMPLETED AND CERTIFIED IN ENTREPRENEURSHIP DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM FROM (C.T.T.C) BHUBANESWAR.
- PARTICIPATED IN SCIENCE EXHIBITION IN SCHOOL.